Matthew J VanZoeren

mattvanzoeren@gmail.com (856)383-5703

Driven chemist with three years of experience providing instruction and guidance in proper laboratory chemical safety. Fast learning, versatile physics major who excels under pressure and time constraints.

Self-taught Full Stack web developer-JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ¡Query, node.js, mySQL, mongoDB, React.js, PHP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tradebe Environmental Services, LLC - Operations Manager

(Feb.2019-March 2020)

11 North Avenue, Dunellen, NJ 08012

- Led a team of chemists to inspect and analyze laboratories for EPA compliance and evaluate necessary chemical removal
- Maintained a breadth of knowledge of current EHS, OSHA and DEP regulations to ensure site personnel are operating safely and following proper procedures
- Met with EPA officials to discuss ongoing changes in chemical transport and handling guidelines
- Trained new chemists on SOPs, EPA, and DOT procedures to ensure compliance with government regulations
- Managed transport and organization of teams to travel to customer sites such as laboratories, hospitals, and manufacturing facilities per DOT guidelines
- Oversaw purchasing and procurement of supplies using SAP as well as maintain P/L forms for the New Jersey division

Tradebe Environmental Services, LLC - Field Chemist

(Sept. 2017 - Feb. 2019)

11 North Avenue, Dunellen, NJ 08012

- Analyzed chemicals at labs and manufacturing sites to assess the dangers relating to storage and transportation, as well as any dangers that might come from long term storage and exposure
- Led a small team in drafting SOPs and Site Safety Plans regarding EHS guidelines on customer sites
- Created manifests and land disposal restriction forms following EPA and DOT guidelines for safely and correctly analyzing and removing chemicals from laboratories
- Assisted laboratories and other facilities in maintaining a safe and compliant work environment

EDUCATION

Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ

Bachelor of Arts in Physics

UNDERGRADUATE ACTIVITIES

Rutgers University Society of Physics Students

(Jan. 2013 - May 2016)

• Partook in weekly discussions and debates about current theories in science and physics

Rutgers University Habitat for Humanity

(Jan. 2013 - May 2016)

Volunteered to gather money and build homes on behalf of those less fortunate